Register of the Ralph de Toledano Papers, 1918-1971
Hoover Institution Archives
Ralph de Toledano Papers,
1918-1971
71030
Toledano, Ralph de, 1916-
9 manuscript boxes, 1 envelope (3.7 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, writings, and printed matter, relating to American communism, politics, and journalism, and the Alger Hiss espionage case. Includes 98 letters from Whittaker Chambers about the Hiss case.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1971.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Chambers, Whittaker.; Hiss, Alger.; Communism.; Communism--United States.; Espionage, Russian--United States.; Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation); United States--Politics and government.; Conservatism.; Journalists.
Biographical Note
1916 August 17 Born, International Zone, Tangier, Morocco
1938 B.A., Columbia University
1941-1943 Associate Editor, New Leader
1946 Editor, Standard
1946-1947 Managing Editor, Plain Talk
1948 Assistant Editor, Newsweek
1949-1960 Associate Editor, Newsweek
1950 Author, Seeds of Treason
1954 Author, Day of Reckoning Author, Nixon
1956-1960 Washington correspondent, Newsweek
1960-1971 Syndicated columnist, King Features Syndicate
1960- President, National News-Research Inc. Associate Editor, National Review
1960 Author, Lament for a Generation
1963 Author, The Greatest Plot in History Author, The Winning Side
1964 Author, The Conservative Papers
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, writings, and printed matter, relating to American communism, politics, and journalism, and the Alger Hiss espionage case. Includes 98 letters from Whittaker Chambers about the Hiss case.
Container List
- Correspondence, 1949-1971 (Boxes 1-2)
  Correspondence arranged alphabetically by last name of correspondent.
  - Unidentified (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A (Folder 2)
  - Agnew, Spiro T. (Folder 3)
  - Ashbrook, John M. (Folder 4)
  - Atkins, Ollie (Folder 5)
  - B (Folder 6)
  - Barzun, Jacques (Folder 7)
  - Bergida, Heddy (Folder 8)
  - Berlin, Richard E. (Folder 9)
  - Bramble, Oakley R. (Folder 10)
  - Buchanan, Patrick J. (Folder 11)
  - Buckley, James L. (Folder 12)
  - Buckley, William F. (Folder 13)
  - C (Folder 14)
  - Chambers, Esther (Folder 15)
  - Chapin, Dwight L. (Folder 16)
  - Chotiner, Murray M. (Folder 17)
  - D (Folder 18)
  - De Sola Pool, D. (Folder 19)
  - Dirksen, Everett M. (Folder 20)
  - Dos Passos, John (Folder 21)
  - Dwoskin, Charles (Folder 22)
  - E (Folder 23)
  - Ervin, Sam J., Jr. (Folder 24)
  - F (Folder 25)
  - Fannin, Paul (Folder 26)
  - Finch, Robert H. (Folder 27)
  - Freeman, Neal B. (Folder 28)
  - G (Folder 29)
  - Goldwater, Barry (Folder 30)
  - H (Folder 31)
  - Hoover, Herbert (Folder 32)
  - Hoover, J. Edgar (Folder 33)
  - I-J (Folder 34)
  - Javits, Jacob (Folder 35)
  - K (Folder 36)
  - Klein, Herb (Folder 37)
  - L (Folder 38)
  - Laird, Melvin (Folder 39)
  - Loeb, William (Folder 40)
  - Lyons, Eugene (Folder 41)
  - M (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - McCaffrey, Neil (Folder 2)
  - Minton, Walter J. (Folder 3)
  - Moley, Raymond (Folder 4)
  - Moreell, Ben (Folder 5)
  - Murphy, George (Folder 6)
  - N (Folder 7)
  - Nixon, Richard M. (Folder 8)
  - O (Folder 9)
  - P (Folder 10)
  - Parkinson, Gaylord B. (Folder 11)
  - R (Folder 12)
  - Reagan, Ronald (Folder 13)
  - Rhodes, John J. (Folder 14)
  - Rusher, William A. (Folder 15)
  - S (Folder 16)
  - T (Folder 17)
  - U-V (Folder 18)
  - W (Folder 19)
  - Wedemeyer, A.C. (Folder 20)
  - Yorty, Sam (Folder 21)
  - X-Z (Folder 22)
- Writings, 1940-1970 (Boxes 2-4)
  Drafts and published copies of newspaper columns and articles, magazine articles, essays, speeches, poems, notes, bibliography, and reviews. Arranged by form.
  - King Features Column, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 23-24)
  - King Features Column, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Newspaper articles (Folder 3)
  - Magazine articles (Folder 4)
  - Political essays, "The Goldwater Story" (Folder 5)
  - Political essays (Folder 6)
  - Essays, General (Folder 7)
  - Reports to The Nation (Lavine), 1957-1958 (Folder 8)
  - Speech written for Richard Nixon (Folder 9)
  - Speeches ghostwritten by Ralph de Toledano (Folder 10)
  - Poetry (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Ideas for books and articles (Folder 2)
  - Bibliography (Folder 3)
  - Reviews (Folder 4)
  - Reviews of Seeds of Treason (Folder 5)
- Subject File, 1926-1972 (Boxes 4-6)
  Correspondence, reports, memoranda, notes, printed matter, and newspaper clippings. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Agencia de Informaciones Peridisticas (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Amerasia case (Folder 7)
  - American Conservative Union (Folder 8)
  - Americans for Constitutional Action (Folder 9)
  - Biographical sketches (Folder 10)
  - Bridges, Harry (Folder 11)
  - Chambers, Whittaker (Folder 12)
  - Committee on Un-American Activities, list of publications (Folder 13)
  - Communist Party in the United States (Folder 14)
  - Communist Party in the United States, memoranda of Ralph de Toledano and Christopher T. Emmet, 1946-1947 (Folder 15)
  - Currie, Lauchlin (Folder 16)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation (Folder 17)
  - Gouzenko, Igor (Folder 18)
  - Guatemala, U.S. intervention (Folder 19)
  - Hiss-Chambers case (Box 5)
    - General. Clipping and notes (Folder 1)
    - Letters from Hiss supporters (Folder 2)
    - Memorandum on case by Richard Nixon, 1949 February 1 (Folder 3)
  - Kennedy, John F. (Folder 4)
  - Khrushchev, Nikita (Folder 5)
  - Kirov, Sergei M. (Folder 6)
  - Latin American Report (Folder 7)
  - Levine, Isaac Don (Folder 8)
  - McCarthy, Joseph (Folder 9)
  - Moroccan Jews, 1941 (Folder 10)
  - National Press Club (Folder 11)
  - Nixon, Richard M.
    - Presidential trip to Austria, U.S.S.R., Iran, and Poland, 1972 May-June
      - Schedules and lists (Folder 12)
      - Lists of accompanying press (Folder 13)
      - Press conferences (Folder 14)
      - Official press releases (Folder 15)
      - Press reports (Folder 16)
  - Nuclear weapons testing (Folder 17)
  - Political intelligence (Folder 18)
  - Republican Party
    - Proceedings of the Hershey Unity Conference, 1964 August 12 (Folder 19)
    - Minutes of the Republican National Committee meeting, 1965 January 21-22 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Sorge spy case (Folder 2)
  - Soviet Union
    - "Entry of the Soviet Union into War against Japan, 1941-1945" (Folder 3)
    - Relations with the Far East (Folder 4)
  - Tresca murder case and the Communist Party in Mexico (Folder 5)
  - Wallach spy case (Folder 6)
  - Yugoslavia, O.S.S. report, 1944 June (Folder 7)
- Printed Material, 1918-1969 (Box 6)
  Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, printed articles and a pamphlet. Arranged chronologically.
  - Newspaper clippings, pamphlet and printed articles (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Printed transcript of the perjury trial of Alger Hiss in the U.S. District Court for the Southern District of New York, 1949-1950 (Box 7-8)
- Whittaker Chambers letters and transcriptions, 1949-1962 (Box 9)
- Photographs of Ralph de Toledano, 6 prints / 1 envelope (Box A)